RESUME

A H M ERFANULLAH



I am an aspiring supply chain professional with more than eight years of experience at multiple renowned companies like Incepta Pharma, Square Pharma, Energypac and GE Healthcare Bangladesh Ltd. My deep professional experience is complemented with my strong academic background of graduating in the discipline of mechanical engineering from Islamic University of Technology. I aim to extend and deepen my professional footprint at a global level while being a part of or leading a dynamic team in a learning environment.











PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Customer Solutions Specialist (August 2018- Present) / GE Healthcare Bangladesh Ltd.

Key Responsibilities:

- Leading the healthcare spare parts import operation of Bangladesh
- Guiding field engineers to assign parts according to a service request
- Facilitating global sourcing team for smooth operation of both open and back orders
- Generating proforma invoice, opening and amending LC if necessary
- Checking and approving commercial invoices and packing lists for shipments
- Coordinating with Insurance company for cover note, addendum and policy
- · Organizing shipping guarantees and duty pay-order from bank for customs clearance
- Advising CnF team for smooth clearance of goods from customs
- Coordinating with DHL team for perfect allocation of local inventory in warehouse and ensuring timely customer site delivery
- · Collaborating with internal and external audit team for inventory management

Executive, Supply Chain Management (November 2016- August 2018) / Energypac Power Generation Ltd.

Key Responsibilities:

- · Checking current stock report & getting approval for new demands from higher management
- Collecting quotation & negotiating price with supplier
- Preparing both technical and commercial comparative statement
- Creating purchase order
- Processing bills and submitting to A/F dept. after the delivery
- Collecting proforma invoice from supplier
- Preparing Letter of Credit / CAD / TT
- Arranging insurance for shipping consignments
- · Maintaining continuous communication with suppliers and banks regarding proper documentation
- Following up shipment status regularly
- Appointing designated CnF agent for customs clearance upon arrival of goods
- Arranging the payment of customs duty in time and clearance of goods from customs
- Receiving goods at the warehouse and sorting accordingly
- Arranging local transport for the smooth delivery at site

Executive, Technical Services (September 2014- July 2015) / Square Pharmaceuticals Ltd.

Key Responsibilities:

- Exploring new sources of machines, equipment and services
- Managing sales & service contracts with the suppliers
- Procuring capital machinery & utilities
- Preparing weekly assessment report on market need & its fulfillment
- Preparing documents for technical & commercial bidding
- Attending technical & commercial meeting with different business houses
- Visiting suppliers or vendors for strengthening business relations

Officer, Technical Services (March 2013 - September 2014) / Incepta Pharmaceuticals Ltd.

Key Responsibilities:

- Collecting quotations according to the purchase requirement
- Analyzing the quotations and choosing the best offer
- Negotiating price with the suppliers
- Issuing the purchase order and forwarding it to the commercial department
- Ensuring the after-sales service where needed
- Maintaining the log book of the purchase indents and purchase orders issued

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

• B. Sc Engg. (MCE) | 2012

Islamic University of Technology (IUT), Gazipur | CGPA: 3.32/4.00

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) | 2008
 Notre Dame College, Dhaka | GPA: 5.00/5.00

Secondary School Certificate (SSC) | 2006
 Ideal School & College, Dhaka | GPA: 5.00/5.00

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Served as a procurement supervisor for a project- Generator Assembling Plant and succeeded in curtailing procurement cost of the said project by 30%
- Reduced turnaround time for import operation of medical equipments by 35%
- Introduced two new processes in import operations that allowed to generate significant savings for the concerned company
- Received Global Customer Solutions award for remarkable performance during COVID-19 pandemic

TRAININGS

• Strategic Supply Chain Management

Topics: Fundamentals of Supply Chain, Planning, Sourcing & Procurement, Manufacturing, Inventory Management, Logistics & Information System

Institute of Professional Development Programs

• Shipping Procedures for Export, Import & Customs Formalities

Topics: Procedures, techniques, methodology and ideas related to different aspects of shipping required for operating international trade effectively and to reduce cost and lead time of export and Import

Institute: DCCI Business Institute

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Sourcing
- Negotiation
- Procurement
- Logistics
- Inventory Control
- Vendor management
- Project management

REFERENCES

Tania Mustafa
 General Manager
 Incepta Pharmaceuticals Ltd.
 +8801713160406

taniamustafa@inceptapharma.com

Baburaj NJ
 Customer Solutions Manager
 GE Healthcare
 +919741906458
 baburaj.nj@ge.com